在早期的一次演讲中，我们介绍了滚动，俯仰，偏航角度的概念。它的
In a much earlier lecture, we introduced the notion of roll, pitch, yaw angles. It’s
一种直观的方式来思考身体在太空中的方向，我们可以思考
an intuitive way to think about the orientation of a body in space and we can think about
它是许多基本轮换的产物。它是围绕x轴的旋转
it as the product of a number of elementary rotations. It’s a rotation around the x-axis
通过滚动角，围绕y轴旋转俯仰角，以及围绕旋转
by the roll angle, a rotation around the y-axis by the pitch angle, and a rotation around
z轴是偏航角。现在，我们可以采取这种衍生物
the z-axis by the yaw angle. Now, we could take the derivative of this
表达式，我们获得旋转矩阵的变化率的关系
expression and we obtain a relationship for the rate of change of the rotation matrix
就一些基本旋转矩阵而言。一些基本轮换的衍生物
in terms of some elementary rotation matrices. The derivatives of some elementary rotation
矩阵，以及这里表示的侧倾角，俯仰角和偏航角的导数
matrices, and the derivative of the roll angle, pitch angle and yaw angle which are here denoted
分别由rdot，pdot和ydot表示。我们也知道a的时间导数
by r dot, p dot and y dot, respectively. We also know that the time derivative of a
旋转矩阵可以用作为函数的斜对称矩阵表示
rotation matrix can be expressed in terms of a skew-symmetric matrix which is a function
角速度和旋转矩阵本身。我可以重新安排这个相当复杂的
of angular velocity and the rotation matrix itself. I can rearrange this rather complex
表达式，因此对于斜对称矩阵，s。然后，我可以将有限元等同起来
expression and so for the skew-symmetric matrix, s. And then, I can equate the finite elements
在我的等式的左手边和右手边之间的s。
of s between the left and right hand side of my equation.
结果是角速度，ω和变化率之间的关系
The result is a relationship between angular velocity, omega, and the rates of change of
我的滚动，俯仰和偏航角度。并且，这种关系是另一种雅可比矩阵。
my roll, pitch and yaw angles. And, this relationship is in terms of yet another Jacobian matrix.
它是一个3x3雅可比矩阵，用符号大写字母B表示.B是函数
It’s a 3 x 3 Jacobian matrix and is denoted by the symbol capital B. B is a function of
滚动，俯仰，偏航角度。并且，更确切地说，它是滚动角度和角度的函数
the roll, pitch, yaw angles. And, more precisely, it’s a function of the roll angle and the
俯仰角。偏航角不会出现在雅可比矩阵的表达式中。
pitch angle. The yaw angle does not appear in the expression for this Jacobian matrix.
这是一个很好的关系，因为它链接了一个非常模糊和抽象的数量
This is a nice relationship because it links a very obscure and abstract quantity like
角速度并以滚动，俯仰和偏航率表示它
angular velocity and expresses it in terms of roll, pitch and yaw rates which are much
更直观的工程师。这是我们介绍的表达方式
more intuitive for engineers. Here is the expression that we introduced
早先将机器人关节角度的变化率映射到机器人末端执行器的空间
earlier which maps the rate of change of robot joint angles to the robot end effector spatial
速度。如我们所知，空间速度包括两个组成部分：平移
velocity. The spatial velocity, as we know, comprises two components: the translational
这里将分量和旋转分量表示为角速度矢量。
component and a rotational component expressed here as an angular velocity vector.
我们想要做的是重新定义这个空间速度矢量，使旋转部分
What we'd like to do is to redefine this spatial velocity vector so that the rotational part
现在包含滚动，俯仰和偏航变化率。如果我们要这样做，那么
now contains the roll, pitch and yaw rates of change. If we are going to do that, then
我们需要改变我们对雅可比矩阵本身的定义。所以，我们介绍一个变体
we need to change our definition of the Jacobian matrix itself. So, we introduce a variant
Jacobian矩阵称为JA，它是解析雅可比矩阵并且它是相关的
of the Jacobian matrix called JA and that is the analytic Jacobian matrix and it relates
机器人关节角度随空间速度的变化现在定义为滚动，俯仰和
the change in robot joint angles to spatial velocity defined now with roll, pitch and
偏航角率。为了获得分析雅可比行列式，我们开始
yaw angle rates. To obtain the analytic Jacobian, we start
使用标准的机器人操纵器雅可比矩阵，我们将它预乘这个矩阵，
with the standard robot manipulator Jacobian matrix and we pre-multiply it by this matrix,
包含很多1和0，它还包含3x3雅可比矩阵B的逆矩阵。
contains a lot of 1s and 0s and it also contains the inverse of the 3 x 3 Jacobian matrix B.
B是滚动，俯仰，偏航角度的函数，其由符号大写Gamma表示。
B is a function of the roll, pitch, yaw angles which I denote by the symbol capital Gamma.